Guide to the Lars Onsager Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1930-1976, undated; Series I; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  - University of Oslo, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 133, Reel 2)
  - University of Southern California, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 134, Reel 2)
  - University of Texas at Austin, 1967-1974 (Box 4, Folder 134, Reel 2)
  - University of Wyoming, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 135, Reel 2)
  - Upsala College, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 135, Reel 2)
  - Van Vleck, John H., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 136, Reel 2)
  - Vasilescu, Dane, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 136, Reel 2)
  - Verwey, E.J.W.
    See: box 6, folder 41
  - Wallace, Stephen C., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 137, Reel 2)
  - Wannier, G.H., 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 137, Reel 2)
  - Weizmann Institute of Science, 1972, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 137, Reel 2)
  - Wells, A.F., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 138, Reel 2)
  - Wergeland, Harald, 1968, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 138, Reel 2)
  - Wigner, Eugene P., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 138, Reel 2)
  - Wiley (John) & Sons, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 139, Reel 2)
  - Wilson, William S., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 139, Reel 2)
  - World Federation of Scientific Workers, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 139, Reel 2)
  - Unidentified, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 140, Reel 2)
  - Norwegian and Swedish scientific societies, 1938-1971 (Box 4, Folder 141, Reel 2)
  - Requests for reprints(*), 1940, 1960-1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 142, Reel 2)
  - Requests for information for biographical, directories, 1960, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 143, Reel 2)
  - Christmas cards, 1972, 1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 144, Reel 2)
  - Mailing addresses, undated (Box 4, Folder 145, Reel 2)
  - Requests for autographs(*), 1969-1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 146, Reel 2)
  - Letters from eccentrics(*), 1940-1976 (Box 4, Folder 147, Reel 2)
- RESEARCH MATERIAL, [pre-1930?]-1976; Series II; 4 linear feet (10 boxes)
  The sections are in this order: Dielectrics, Electrolytes, Ice, Irreversible Processes, Thermal Diffusion, Ising Model, Metals and Semi-Conductors, Liquid Helium, Hydrodynamics, Surface Tension, Origin of Life, Mathematics, Unclassified. There is no overall order within the sections, but folders on the same subject that were found together have been kept together.
  The folder headings in Series II are combinations of Onsager's own words with descriptions provided by the scientists who examined the material as an aid to the arrangement. They are not comprehensive, but suggestive. All of Onsager's words are in quotation marks, and all quotations and citations are his own unless otherwise attributed. Descriptions by the scientists who helped identify the research material are marked with their initials: SM for Stefan Machlup, PAL for Philip A. Lyons, AP for Andrew Patterson, Jr., RMF for Raymond M. Fuoss, JN for John Nagle. If Onsager put a heading on his original folder, it appears in quotation marks as the first item in the heading of the archival folder. Other Onsager quotations are taken from the contents of the folder.
  - Dielectrics
    - Dielectric constant of hydrogen fluoride;1972?-SM (Box 5, Folder 1, Reel 3)
    - "Lattices, Numerical"/TS/"Electrets"/"Potential of plane lattice with charges [and] dipoles" (Box 5, Folder 2, Reel 3)
    - "f[ace]-c[entered] c[ubic] structure: Elastic Spectrum" (Box 5, Folder 3, Reel 3)
    - "Reaction Field, DK"/polymers, infinite chain-SM/von Arkel and Snoek (Box 5, Folder 4, Reel 3)
    - "Dipoles: Green's Theorem"/probably background information for theory of liquid dielectric constants-PAL (Box 5, Folder 5, Reel 3)
    - "Seignette-Electrics Below Curie Point" (Box 5, Folder 6, Reel 3)
    - "Ice-like Seignette-Electrics"/Curie point, NO-SM (Box 5, Folder 7, Reel 3)
    - Dielectrics (Box 5, Folder 7, Reel 3)
      See: Box 5, folders 31-34 See: Box 6, folder 37 See: Box 6, folder 41 See: Box 7, folder 52-53 See: Box 7, folder 55 See: Box 7, folder 61 See: Box 8, folder 74 See: Box 10, folder 115 See: Box 12, folder 147
  - Electrolytes
    - Wien effect, 1971-SM/MS fragment/"nothing new-a historical review, then takeoff on electrons in liquid helium"-AP (Box 5, Folder 8, Reel 3)
    - Wien effect, active transport, late 1969?-SM/1971 (Box 5, Folder 9, Reel 3)
    - "Random Coil"/electrostatics of polyelectrolyte chain-PAL (Box 5, Folder 10, Reel 3)
    - "Electrode Polarization" (Box 5, Folder 11, Reel 3)
    - "Self-avoiding chain"/l (Box 5, Folder 12, Reel 3)
    - "Self-avoiding chain"/2/M.E. Fisher and D.S. Gaunt, "Ising Model and Self-Avoiding Walks on Hypercubical Lattices and 'High-Density' Expansions," Phys. Rev. 133, No. lA, A 224-A 239 (1964) (Box 5, Folder 13, Reel 3)
    - "Electrophoresis 'exact' "/"has historical interest; part was published in Onsager and Fuoss, 'The Conductance of Symmetrical Electrolytes. III. Electrophoresis' (no. 55)"-RMF (Box 5, Folder 14, Reel 3)
    - Concentrated Electrolytes /MS, "Theories of Concentrated Electrolytes" (no. 10)/related calculations labeled "Gürtelberg Principle," "Approach to Debye-Hückel K.," "Distribution function. Attempt for binary electrolyte," "Error in Grunwall approximation," "Miscellaneous," " #n," and unlabeled (Box 5, Folder 15, Reel 3)
    - "Electrolytes C-C"/"much is a preliminary to articles in J. Phys. Chem. (nos. 51, 54, 55, 59, 63)"-RMF (Box 5, Folder 16, Reel 3)
    - "Poisson-Boltzmann"/TS, "Theory of the Electric Double Layer"/TS, "The Poisson-Boltzmann Equation in Cylindrical Coordinates"/1950/"probably related to Onsager and Kim, 'The Relaxation Effect in Mixed Strong Electrolytes' (no. 41)"-AP (Box 5, Folder 17, Reel 3)
    - "Poisson-Boltzmann" (Box 5, Folder 18, Reel 3)
    - "Recomb[ination]-Relaxation"/"I cannot date this exactly but the ideas entered largely into his Wien effect papers"-AP (Box 5, Folder 19, Reel 3)
    - "Recomb[ination]-Relax[ation]"/"these ideas entered into his Wien effect papers"-AP/Langevin diffusion-SM (Box 5, Folder 20, Reel 3)
    - "'Polarization' in Wien effect cells"/"estimates of relaxation times, apparently"-AP (Box 5, Folder 21, Reel 3)
    - "Freezing Potentials"/Poisson equation?-SM (Box 5, Folder 22, Reel 3)
    - "Relax[ation]-Electrophoresis"/1968 (Box 5, Folder 23, Reel 3)
    - "Water Relaxation"/"Force on oscillating sphere"/"Wyman"/ Lamb, p. 633+ (Box 5, Folder 24, Reel 3)
    - "Problems"/diffusion in electrolytes-SM/"thoughts, no obvious conclusions"-AP (Box 5, Folder 25, Reel 3)
    - "Wien effect, Strong Electrolytes"/TL, Onsager to [underline] Eckstrom, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 26, Reel 3)
    - "Bijl"/kinetic theory-SM/"Momentum quantized in resting frame of reference" (Box 5, Folder 27, Reel 3)
    - "Cataphoresis" (Box 5, Folder 28, Reel 3)
    - "Dissociation Constants and Sundry"/"The variation of ionic mobilities with the field for HCl and for HAc at 25°" (Box 5, Folder 29, Reel 3)
    - "Ionic at[mosphere]s, 2 [frequencies]" (Box 5, Folder 30, Reel 3)
    - "Data"/"CoCl 2 in Acetone"/Gemant, Liquid Dielectrics (1933) (Box 5, Folder 31, Reel 3)
    - "Data on Conduction in Strong Fields"/Gemant, p. 89/ H. Schiller, Ann. Physik [4], 81, 32 (1926) (Box 5, Folder 32, Reel 3)
    - "Velocities in Ion Pairs"/Wien effect-RMF (Box 5, Folder 33, Reel 3)
    - "DK of Gemant's benzene solutions"/"I think these are preliminary calculations on theory of relaxation field in dielectrics-published about 1934"-RMF/ "Falkenhagen theory" (Box 5, Folder 34, Reel 3)
    - Electrolytes?-SM/1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 35, Reel 3)
    - "Electrolytes"/"The Relaxation Effects in Mixed Strong Electrolytes" (no. 41)/ALS, Roy C. Gunter, Jr., to Onsager, 1973/MS, "Transport Processes in Strong Electrolytes"; 1973?-SM/"A Correction to the Poisson-Boltzmann Equation for Unsymmetrical Electrolytes" (no. 58) (Box 6, Folder 36, Reel 3)
    - "Auxiliary to Dev[iation from] Ohm's Law."/Gemant, pp. 78-79/"Acetone" (Box 6, Folder 37, Reel 3)
    - "Diffusion of Electrophoretic Boundary" (Box 6, Folder 38, Reel 3)
    - "[Joseph F.] Malerba"/freezing potential/Malerba MS/ALS (copy), John F. Nagle to Max Hubman, 1976/ALS, Joseph Hubbard to Onsager, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 39, Reel 3)
    - "Freezing Potentials"/"His interest was protonic jumping in ice"-AP/1962 (Box 6, Folder 40, Reel 4)
    - "Tactoids"/"Effects of Shape on the Interaction of Colloidal Particles" (no. 28)/TS, "Anisotropic Solutions of Colloids" (no. 21)/TS, "Crystal Statistics" (no. 22) (Box 6, Folder 41, Reel 4)
    - Unidentified (Box 6, Folder 42, Reel 4)
    - T.H. Einwohner, "Alternating Current Conductance of Mixed Electrolytes," Yale Ph.D., 1963 (Box 6, Folder 43, Reel 4)
    - Publication nos. 38, 40, 42, 58/M.-S. Chen, "The Conductance of Mixed Strong Electrolytes at Finite Concentrations," Yale Ph.D., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 44, Reel 4)
    - Onsager and A.M. Stewart, "Asymptotic Forms for Luminescent Intensity Due to Donor-Acceptor Pair Recombination," research supported by Air Force Office of Scientific Research Grant Number AFOSR-72-2298 (Box 6, Folder 45, Reel 4)
    - "University of Miami"/Chia-tsun Liu, "The Effect of Screening of the Ionic Atmosphere on the Theory of Wien Effect in Weak Electrolytes," Yale Ph.D., 1965/1973? (Box 6, Folder 46, Reel 4)
    - Neville R. Kallenbach, "The Microviscosity of Electrolyte Solutions," Yale Ph.D., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 47, Reel 4)
    - Unidentified/1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 48, Reel 4)
    - MS, "Kinetic Depolarization of Solvents by Ion Migration"/ partial MS, "Hopping of Ions on Ice" (no. 78)/MS, "Dielectric Dispersion in Ionic Conductors" (Box 6, Folder 49, Reel 4)
    - Unidentified/1973? (Box 7, Folder 50, Reel 4)
    - "Mostly electrolytes, etc. Should be examined by Hubbard and Chen. Perhaps some mathematical tricks of interest"-JN(l)/TS(copy), "We should bear in mind that purely electrical measurements do not distinguish between different kinds of current…"/1967-1976? (Box 7, Folder 51, Reel 4)
    - "Mostly electrolytes…"-JN(2)/MS, "The Dielectric Dispersion of Electrolyte Solutions" (Box 7, Folder 52, Reel 4)
    - "Mostly electrolytes…"-JN(3)/MS, "Reduction of Dielectric Polarization by the Migration of Ions" (Box 7, Folder 53, Reel 4)
    - Mostly electrolytes...-JN(4)/M. Born, "Über die Beweglichkeit der Electrolytischen Ionen"/MS(copy), TS, "We should bear in mind that purely electrical measurements do not distinguish between different kinds of current... (Box 7, Folder 54, Reel 4)
    - MS, "We, should bear in mind…"/Malerba, 1976/MS, "Freezing Potentials" (Box 7, Folder 55, Reel 4)
    - Conductance?-SM (Box 7, Folder 56, Reel 4)
    - "Joseph B. Hubbard"/MS, "For a few years now we have suspected that in good liquid ionic conductors a kinetic coupling between the ion migration and the dielectric relaxation generally entails a reduction of the 'static' dielectrical constant…" (Box 7, Folder 57, Reel 4)
      See: Folio
    - "Electrode effects: notes, very sketchy, 1976?"-SM (Box 7, Folder 58, Reel 4)
    - Electrolytes (Box 7, Folder 58, Reel 4)
      See: Box 9, folder 92 See: Box 10, folder 115 See: Box 11, folder 123-124 See: Box 11, folder 137 See: Box 11, folder 139 See: Box 12, folder 147 See: Box 12, folder 162
  - Ice
    - "C log C"/Ice, Bjerrum fault, ion transport in crystals-SM (Box 7, Folder 59, Reel 4)
    - "KD 2PO 4-# D"/relaxation and polarization-PAL/ KD 2PO 4 -R.M. Mill and S.K. Ichiki, Phys. Rev. 130, 150/ triglycine sulphate-Phys. Rev. 128, 1140 (Box 7, Folder 60, Reel 4)
    - "Ice, etc."/temperature coefficients of dielectric constant-SM/MS fragment, "Chain Association in Polar Liquids"/E.W. Montroll, "Statistical Mechanics of Nearest Neighbor Systems" (Box 7, Folder 61, Reel 4)
    - "Ice, Miscell."/number of chains of at least two molecules-SM (Box 7, Folder 62, Reel 4)
    - "KH 2PO 4 Dipoles Ice"/F. London and M. Polanyi, J. Phys. Chem. 11B, 222 (1930)/M. Polanyi, Trans. Far. Soc. 28, 316 (1932)/Lennard-Jones, Trans. Far. Soc. 28, 333 (1932)/S.C. Wang, Physik. Z. 28, 663 (1927) (Box 7, Folder 63, Reel 4)
    - "Div[ergence] Clusters" (Box 7, Folder 64, Reel 4)
    - "Protonics"/notes for talk (Box 7, Folder 65, Reel 4)
    - "Ice"/"Dihedral subgroup"/1959/A. Einstein, Ann. d. Physik. 17, 549 (1905) (Box 8, Folder 66, Reel 5)
    - "H+ Motion"/TS abstract, "Ion Motion and Dielectric Relaxation"/"Dr. R.S. Freund, Bell Telephone Labs" (Box 8, Folder 67, Reel 5)
    - "Lorentzen"/MS, "Introductory Lecture" / "proton migration on Bethe lattice"; calculations only-SM (Box 8, Folder 68, Reel 5)
    - W. Drost-Hansen, proposal for "Studies of Amorphous Ice," 1974 (Box 8, Folder 69, Reel 5)
    - Isao Minagawa, "A Theory of the Mobility of (H 30)+ Defects in Ice Crystals"/2 ALS, Minagawa to Onsager, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 70, Reel 5)
    - "Hopping of Ions on Ice" (no. 78) (Box 8, Folder 71, Reel 5)
    - "Ice (Zurich)" (Box 8, Folder 72, Reel 5)
    - "Ice"/J.A. Sussman, "The Theory of Proton Transfer in Hydrogen Bonded Solids"/J.H. Schmitt, "Dynamical Effects of Deuteron Intrabond in KD 2PO 4" (Box 8, Folder 73, Reel 5)
    - J.F. Nagle, "Dielectric Constant of Ice," J. Chem. Phys. 61, 883-888 (1974) (Box 8, Folder 74, Reel 5)
    - Ice (Box 8, Folder 74, Reel 5)
      See: Box 5, folder 7 See: Box 6, folder 40 See: Box 6, folder 49
  - Irreversible Processes
    - Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 75, Reel 5)
    - Irreversible Processes (Box 8, Folder 75, Reel 5)
      See: Box 12, folder 147
  - Thermal Diffusion
    - "He[lium] Therm[al] Diffusion"/ 3He- 4He isotope separation-SM (Box 8, Folder 76, Reel 5)
    - "Thermal Diffusion" (Box 8, Folder 77, Reel 5)
    - "Isotopes by Soret Effect"/"On the Theory of Isotope Separation by Thermal Diffusion" (no. 17)/ correspondence between Onsager and W.R. Furry, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 78, Reel 5)
    - "He[lium] + Ne[on]" (Box 8, Folder 79, Reel 5)
    - MS, "Transient Phenomena in Diffusion Column" (Box 8, Folder 80, Reel 5)
    - "Isotopes by Thermal Diffusion"/TS, "On the Theory of Isotope Separation by Thermal Diffusion" (no. 17) (Box 9, Folder 81, Reel 5)
    - "Entropy Efficiency"/"Thermal Diffusion"/ordinary diffusion-SM/efficiency of isotope separation-SM (Box 9, Folder 82, Reel 5)
    - "H 2by Migration"/"Mobilities of H 1 and H 2 at 0Â°. Conductance of HCl at 0Â°"/TS, "Flow due to diffusion" (Box 9, Folder 83, Reel 5)
    - "0 2 + e - "/"0 2 electron transport"-Schultz and Dowell, Phys. Rev. 128, 174, and Schultz, Phys. Rev. 128, 178/"e - + 0 2 attachment"-Conway, J. Chem. Phys. 36, 2549 (1962) (Box 9, Folder 84, Reel 5)
    - "Dissipation"/gas transport in the centrifuge-SM/ entropy source density-SM (Box 9, Folder 85, Reel 5)
    - "v[an] d[er] Waals-Collision" (Box 9, Folder 86, Reel 5)
    - "Fringe Method"/Onsager and L.J. Gosting, "General Theory for the Gouy Diffusion Method" (no. 33) (Box 9, Folder 87, Reel 5)
    - "Collisions in gases"/kinetic theory, collision integral-SM (Box 9, Folder 88, Reel 5)
    - "Gas Theory" (Box 9, Folder 89, Reel 5)
    - "Clouds"/"supersaturation factor, equilibrium rate of evap[oratio]n" (Box 9, Folder 90, Reel 5)
    - "Zeeman Effect of Free Paths" (Box 9, Folder 91, Reel 5)
    - "Thermal Diffusion"/Mou-Shan Chen, "The Conductance of Mixed Strong Electrolytes at Finite Concentrations," Yale Ph.D., 1969/P.K. Gupta and A.R. Cooper, Jr., "The [D] Matrix for Multicomponent Diffusion" (Box 9, Folder 92, Reel 5)
    - "Isotopes by Thermal Diffusion, Numerical"/"On the Theory of Isotope Separation by Thermal Diffusion" (no. 17) (Box 9, Folder 93, Reel 5)
    - Thermal Diffusion (Box 9, Folder 93, Reel 5)
      See: Box 5, folder 27 See: Box 7, folder 64 See: Box 13, folder 182
  - Ising Model
    - "(C[rystal] S[tatistics] I.) Ising Model" (Box 9, Folder 94, Reel 5)
    - "Bruria Kaufman" (1)/untitled TS of B. Kaufman, "Crystal Statistics. II"/correspondence between Kaufman and Onsager, 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 95, Reel 5)
    - "Bruria Kaufman" (2)/untitled TS of B. Kaufman, "Crystal Statistics. II"/untitled TS of B. Kaufman and Onsager, "Crystal Statistics. III" (no. 29)/correspondence between Kaufman and Onsager, 1947-1950 (Box 9, Folder 96, Reel 6)
    - "C[rystal] S[tatistics] II, III"/TS(copy), B. Kaufman, "Crystal Statistics. II"/TS(copy), B. Kaufman and Onsager, "Crystal Statistics. III" (no. 29)/correspondence between Kaufman and Onsager, 1946 and 1950/TS, "Solution of the Differential Equation" (Box 9, Folder 97, Reel 6)
    - "Crystal pseudo potentials" (Box 9, Folder 98, Reel 6)
    - "Lattices, Formulas"/numerical computations-SM (Box 9, Folder 99, Reel 6)
    - "Neighborhood in Polymer"/Berlin and Montroll, J. Chem. Phys. (1952) (Box 9, Folder 100, Reel 6)
    - "Rectangular Lattice II-V"/TS, "We first define the two sets of operators…"/"Wannier Transformation"/TS, "Bloch-type operators and characteristic vectors" (Box 10, Folder 101, Reel 6)
    - Bloch-type operators-SM (Box 10, Folder 102, Reel 6)
    - C.J. Thompson and M.J. Wardrop, "Critical Points of Two-Dimensional Ising Models," J. Phys. A: Math., Nucl. Gen. 7, L65-69 (1974) (Box 10, Folder 103, Reel 6)
    - "Lecture notes"/"#-Transitions"/resistivity-SM (Box 10, Folder 104, Reel 6)
  - Metals and Semiconductors
    - "Low T[emperature] Sp[ecific] Heat: Crystals"/TLS, R.M. Mazo to Onsager, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 105, Reel 6)
    - "Sp[ecific] Heat of Crystals at Low Temp[erature]s" (Box 10, Folder 106, Reel 6)
    - "de Haas-van. Alphen Effect"/"Interpretation of the de Haas-van Alphen Effect," Phil. Mag. 43, 1006 (1951) (Box 10, Folder 107, Reel 6)
    - Graph, "Specific heat curve for n-hexdecylalcohol" (Box 10, Folder 108, Reel 6)
    - Metals and Semiconductors (Box 10, Folder 108, Reel 6)
      See: Box 5, folder 3 See: Box 6, folder 45 See: Box 10, folder 104 See: Box 12, folder 147 See: Box 12, folder 152 See: Box 12, folder 154
  - Liquid Helium
    - (Stevens) He lecture/"Bogoliubov"/"roton. Feynman & Cohen. Frôlich & Kuper"/proof, "Helium II" (no. 57) (Box 10, Folder 109, Reel 6)
    - "He Film" (Box 10, Folder 110, Reel 6)
    - "He: ¼hv" ½/MS, "1) Gradual consumption of det[ergent] indic[ates] that same coats fibers… (Box 10, Folder 111, Reel 6)
    - "Liq[uid] He[lium]"/"Quantization of sound" (Box 10, Folder 112, Reel 6)
    - "He: Surface Tension" (Box 10, Folder 113, Reel 6)
    - "He (mostly Landau)"/"Heat Flow relative to Matter" (Box 10, Folder 114, Reel 6)
    - "He DK" (Box 10, Folder 115, Reel 6)
    - "Low Temp[erature]s"/1946 (Box 10, Folder 116, Reel 6)
    - "Ions in He[lium] liq[uid]"/C. Kuper, Phys. Rev. 122, 1007 (1961) (Box 10, Folder 117, Reel 6)
    - "He[lium]-Order for T[emperature]>0"/second-quantized-SM (Box 10, Folder 118, Reel 6)
    - "e - in He"/Kuper, Phys. Rev. 122, 1007 (1967)/ Atkins, Phys. Rev. 116, 1339 (1959) (Box 10, Folder 119, Reel 6)
    - "He Rotation, etc."/monolamellar; bilamellar; rotons, vortex rings-SM/Bogoliubov and Zubarev, J. Exper. Theor. Phys. USSR 28, 129-39 (1955)/1951-1952? (Box 10, Folder 120, Reel 6)
    - "He: ½h#; #lm"/quantum of circulation-SM (Box 10, Folder 121, Reel 6)
    - "Proton Structure"/Bogoliubov and Zubarev, J. Exper. Theor. Phys. USSR 28, 129 (1955)/excitations of the system of interacting Bose particles-SM (Box 10, Folder 122, Reel 6)
    - Liquid Helium (Box 10, Folder 122, Reel 6)
      See: Box 10, folders 120-122 See: Box 11, folder 137 See: Box 13, folder 183
  - Hydrodynamics
    - "Ion-vortex interaction"/also re: electrolytes-SM (Box 11, Folder 123, Reel 7)
    - "Electrochemical Oscillations" (Box 11, Folder 124, Reel 7)
    - "Viscosity"/TS, "Viscosity in particle shape in colloid solutions" (no.9)/"Evaluation of integrals"/ "Viscosity of ellipsoids in solution. Jeffery'ssolution"/"Force-pair. Relaxation-time. Kinetic energy. Average of φ over directions. Numerical calculations" (Box 11, Folder 125, Reel 7)
    - "Jeffery" (Box 11, Folder 126, Reel 7)
    - "Boundary Layer" (Box 11, Folder 127, Reel 7)
    - "Reynolds Number" (Box 11, Folder 128, Reel 7)
    - Hydrodynamics/Taylor, Proc. Roy. Soc. (1935-1938)/ V. Kármán and Howarth, Proc. Roy. Soc. (1938)/J.M. Burgers, 1929/Oseen, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 129, Reel 7)
    - "Boundary conditions. Flow from origin prescribed" (Box 11, Folder 130, Reel 7)
    - "BK Wave, free boundary, etc." (Box 11, Folder 131, Reel 7)
    - "Turbulence"/"Hydrodynamics (Turbulence)-Kinetic Energy and Dissipation function to sums of squares"/ "Turbulence cascade"/1975?-SM (Box 11, Folder 132, Reel 7)
    - MS(copy), "Detailed Properties of Cylindrical Boundary Layers" (Box 11, Folder 133, Reel 7)
    - "Hydrodynamics? 1970, 1974?"-SM (Box 11, Folder 134, Reel 7)
    - "Turbulence" (Box 11, Folder 135, Reel 7)
    - Hydrodynamics (Box 11, Folder 135, Reel 7)
      See: Box 5, folder 24 See: Box 6, folder 39 See: Box 10, folder 112 See: Box 10, folder 119 See: Box 12, folder 162
  - Surface Tension
    - "Surface Tension"/related to thesis of N Samaras ["Medium Charges in Homogeneous Catalysis and Their Theoretical Interpretation," 1931]?-RMF (Box 11, Folder 136, Reel 7)
    - "Bubble"/surface tension-PAL/energy of formation-SM (Box 11, Folder 137, Reel 7)
    - "123 Gouy Layer"/surface tension-PAL (Box 11, Folder 138, Reel 7)
    - "Landau, Jones-Ray effect"/viscosity of electrolyte solutions, surface tension of liquids in capillaries-PAL/MS, "Wetting of Electrokinetically Active Surfaces. I. Thickness of the Wetting Film"/TS, " General. Adsorption of ions on the walls of the capillary causes the wall to acquire an electrostatical potential…. Computation for a Binary Electrolyte …"/ MS, "Effect of Wall Charge on Capillary Rise" (Box 11, Folder 139, Reel 7)
    - "Adsorption & Capillary"/surface tension in capillaries, elliptic substitution-SM/MS/"Lander transformations" (Box 11, Folder 140, Reel 7)
    - "Electrostatic Adsorption"/surface tension in capillaries-SM/"Drauglis"/"G. Jones" (Box 11, Folder 141, Reel 7)
    - Surface Tension (Box 11, Folder 141, Reel 7)
      See: Box 10, folder 113
  - Origin of Life
    - Voltage clamp-ion pump-SM (Box 11, Folder 142, Reel 7)
    - "Early Days" (Box 11, Folder 143, Reel 7)
    - Conference on Current Flow in Nerve Membranes, 1971 Apr 5-9 (Box 11, Folder 144, Reel 7)
    - "Neurosci: Meet & Org"/1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 145, Reel 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 11, Folder 146, Reel 7)
  - Mathematics
    - Notebook/TS, "Solutions of the Mathieu Equation, of Period 4#, and Certain Related Functions" (abstract of no. 13)/MS, "Error in the Asymptomatic Expansion of Bessel Functions of Imaginary Argument"/MS, "Generalization of the Euler-Maclaurin Sum Formula"/ TS, "Dissociation of Electrolytes in Strong Electric Fields"/MS, "Eigenwerte by Numerical Integration"/ MS, "Consider a dipole of electric moment ¼…"/TS, "Theories of Concentrated Electrolytes" (not identical with no. 10)/"Vibr. galvanometer" (Box 12, Folder 147, Reel 8)
    - "Kriegspiel Theory"/chess-PAL (Box 12, Folder 148, Reel 8)
    - "Zeta Functions" (Box 12, Folder 149, Reel 8)
    - "Flog F"/partition functions-SM (Box 12, Folder 150, Reel 8)
    - "Integral Transformations" (Box 12, Folder 151, Reel 8)
    - "The Exchange Correlation Integral" (Box 12, Folder 152, Reel 8)
    - f(H o +V), (H o+V)½/quantum mechanics; Lippman-Schwimmer?-SM (Box 12, Folder 153, Reel 8)
    - "Electron Compliance"/branch cuts (complex plane)-SM (Box 12, Folder 154, Reel 8)
    - "Consistency"/self-consistent field partition function?-SM (Box 12, Folder 155, Reel 8)
    - "B F[ermions]"/creation-destruction operator formalism-SM (Box 12, Folder 156, Reel 8)
    - "Fermion Interaction"/mimeo, "Many-Electron Wave Function" (no. 45) (Box 12, Folder 157, Reel 8)
    - e Hx½/group theory, one-dimensional representation-SM (Box 12, Folder 158, Reel 8)
    - "Elliptic" (Box 12, Folder 159, Reel 8)
    - "Elliptic on spheres" (Box 12, Folder 160, Reel 8)
    - "Recurrent Determinants, 1940s?"-SM/correspondence with I.I. Hirschman, Jr., 1964 (Box 12, Folder 161, Reel 8)